Christopher Shane Lynn

Bloomington, IL 61704 | 309-445-1633 | christophershanelynn@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/christopher-shane-lynn/ | Portfolio: https://shanelynn.github.io/

PROFILE

Junior **Software and Web Developer** entry level career changer who has passion for technology driving the life change. Has academic and some practical experience in creating/troubleshooting applications with C++, C#, and Java. Also, has experience working with websites in HTML, CSS, PHP, and JavaScript with additional knowledge of databases to create/modify tables and generate data queries all using SQL. Has technical support experience with setting up computer hardware and providing software ticket support. Also, a skilled **Analyst** with 5+ years of experience and over 16 years of professional insurance experience with a Fortune 50 company's corporate HQ. Proven ability in excellent customer service, communication, initiative, critical thinking, and leadership skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS -

Languages & OS: C#, C++, Java, SQL

Operating Systems: Windows (XP, 7, 10), Android, RUMBA Front End: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap

Back End/DBMS: MS-SQL Server, PHP, jQuery, MySQL, MS-Access

Methodologies: Agile Software Development

IDE/Tools: MS Visual Studio, Eclipse, Visual Studio Code, SAS, SAS EG, WinSQL, Mainframe (Rumba), MS

Products (Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Access, Visio), PeopleSoft, GitHub, QlikView, MapInfo,

Crystal Reports, PeopleSoft

Hardware: Diagnostics, Install/Replace Parts and Peripherals, Purchasing

Analysis: Research and Survey Design, Statistics, Reporting, Budget Development, and Consulting

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE -

COLUMBIA COLLEGE, Online and Columbia, MO

06/2020 - Present

Programming Student (Remote)

<u>Projects</u>: Employee Payroll System | C# | Lead Designer and Programmer

Airline Reservation System and CD/DVD Collection System | C++ | Lead Designer and Programmer

Book Store Shopping Cart | Java | Lead Designer and Programmer

Language School Database | SQL | Lead Designer and Programmer

Worked in each language for 2 months and in C++ for 6 months combining to 1+ year total of programming work.

- **C#** Created numerous small console applications to understand the fundamentals of the language. Completed a final project using fundamental knowledge and built a GUI using WinForms that consisted of several forms that input, displayed, stored employee information to a file, and had print functionality. Working on a personal project as time allows designing and developing a simple role-playing game.
- C++ Created numerous console applications to understand the language. Completed two course projects that simulated an airline reservation and CD/DVD collection system while reading data from an external file. Current apps created consist of using pointers, structures, advanced file operations, linked lists, and searches.
- Java Created small console applications for language fundamentals. Completed a final project using JavaFX for a bookstore shopping cart using lists to select items and import inventory data from an external file.
- **SQL** Used queries to create a local relational database and retrieve data from it using SQL Server. Created and modified tables using T-SQL commands, and used ERD design principals.

Christopher Shane Lynn | Page Two

309-445-1633 | christophershanelynn@gmail.com

• **Web Programming** – Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, Bootstrap, and jQuery to design websites. Built a hotel booking website as a course project, and setup an initial portfolio site landing page using GitHub as a static page host. Currently in a self-paced bootcamp learning more intensive developer knowledge and applying that knowledge to create projects.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE —

STATE FARM INSURANCE, Bloomington, IL and Columbia, MO

09/2004 - 03/2021

Workforce Specialist, Human Resources (Office/Remote)

(05/2010 - 03/2021)

<u>Projects</u>: Workforce Specialist Role Creation | Lead Designer

Data COE Department Creation | Analyst & Research

Served as hybrid Workforce and Technical Analyst with a focus on supporting those roles, developing reports, retrieving data, consulting with business partners, creating/modifying programs, and SQL queries.

- Collected, analyzed, and reported on workforce data to aid company leaders/executives in business decisions.
- Survey analysis/design used to create/maintain employee surveys.
- Utilized technical support experience for department employees on workstation hardware/software questions and area evaluation/modification. Aided in updating/debugging software programs.
- Created/updated/maintained SQL tables, queries, and triggers; removed data from SQL tables.
- Created simple Python scripts to automate and display reports.
- Created \$2K in annual expense savings from process improvements and report enhancements.
- Led on two projects. The first enhanced my current role's responsibilities to the professional level, and the second was to setup the workforce data department for the organization.
- Trained new team members and supported business customers with consulting and requirement interpretation.
- Provided data and report expertise to the D&I department for their survey and CEO/executive reports.
- Assisted developing team reports for budget expenses.
- Assisted with research, development, and updates to business policies.

STATE FARM INSURANCE, Columbia, MO

Claim Document Processor, Claims (Office)

(12/2008 - 05/2010)

Projects: Multi-Monitor Workplace Enhancement | Project & Research Lead

- Communicated with claims customers, researching documents and payments, and setting up claims.
- Created \$3K+ in annual expense savings from process improvements, equipment/software implementations, and operating labor leading to multiple special achievement awards for accomplishments.

Imaging Processor I/II, Administrative Services (Office)

(09/2004 - 12/2008)

Projects: CIOS SLA Achievement and Overtime Reduction | Project Lead

- Provided technical support for department employees and the building. Trained to conduct in person workstation hardware setup/removal and software support using a ticket-based switchboard call center.
- Acted as a team lead to ensure team met SLA goals.
- Utilized SQL to maintain an error database; SQL reports could be generated from the database.
- Handled ergonomic support tickets and work area evaluations.
- Served as team lead in a fast-paced environment with heavy workload volume.
- Developed management reports and tracking departmental budget expenses.
- Trained new team members to the department.
- Created \$5K+ in annual expense savings from process improvements and the successful implementation of the CIOS SLA project earning multiple special achievement awards for accomplishments.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED) ————

SCHOLASTIC, INC., Jefferson City, MO

07/2002 - 03/2003

Material Handler | Line Leader, Warehouse

- Restocked inventory for high volume production lines.
- Led other handlers as a line leader, ordered inventory, and provided Q&A as needed.
- Transported freight to lines and created inventory reports for management.

MISSOURI POWER TRANSMISSION, Columbia, MO

06/1998 - 05/2001

Warehouse

<u>Projects</u>: Software Inventory System Update | Lead Technical Support Warehouse Inventory Update | Project Lead

- Provided customer service and retail sales to phone and walk-in customers.
- Managed warehouse inventory by keeping records, purchasing, and stocking supplies.
- Organized daily deliveries for the delivery driver, managed delivery schedules, and assisted delivery driver.
- Implemented a new software inventory system that decreased operating expenses by \$2K a month.
- Designed efficiencies during the Warehouse Inventory Update project that reduced purchasing and labor expenses by \$1K per month.

EDUCATION —

COLUMBIA COLLEGE, Columbia, MO

Associate in Science Degree in Computer Info Systems (08/2021)

Bachelor of Arts Degree in Psychology with a Minor in Sociology (05/2012)

Honors: Summa Cum Laude

CODER FOUNDRY, Kernersville, NC

Certificate of Completion in Full Stack Web Development (self-paced course) (expected 10/2021)